<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<legalnotice id="legalnotice">
         <para>इस पुस्तक को मन्यता प्राप्त है । इस् प्रलेखन को मुफ़्त जिनयो प्रलेखन अधिकार (जि.फ़.द.ल)  वितरन और विकसित किजिये । पाठ १.१ या कोई भी नवीनतम पाठ जो किसी मुफ़्त सॉफ्टवेयर निर्माण द्वारा प्रसारित किया गया हो , बिना किसी परिवतन खंड के । ना आगे ना पिछे गिलाफ मूलशब्द । आप इस दिए गए लिन्क पे इसकी एक प्रति पा सकते है <ulink type="help" url="ghelp:fdl">link</ulink> या फिर COPYING-DOCS फ़ायिल मे इसकी कोपी  वितरित की गयी है ।</para>
          <para>यह नियम-पुस्तक गनोम नियम-पुस्तको का सन्ग्राह का एक  अंश है जो की (गी.फ़.दी.ल) के अन्दर वितरित है । अगर आप इस नियम-पुस्तक को अलग से वितरित करना चाहते है तो आप ऐसा कर सकते है । आपको बस एक लाईसेंस कोपी इस नियम-पुस्तक से जोड़नी होगी । इस्का विवरण धारा ६ मे दिया गया है ।</para>
 
         <para>बहुत सारे नाम जो कम्पनी अपनी उत्पाद और सेवाएँ को अलग करने के लिये रखती है , असल मे व्यापार का चिह्न के रुप मे अधिकारा जाता है । जब ये नाम किसी ग्नोम  प्रलेखन मे आता है तो गनोम  प्रलेखन परियोजना के  सदस्यो को इस व्यापार का चिह्नो की सुचना दे दी जाती है कि नाम बड़े अछरो मै है या छोटे अछरो में ।</para>
 
         <para>प्रलेखन और विकसित प्रलेखन मुफ़्त ग्नोम प्रलेखन धारा के अन्तर्गत है इस समझबुझ के साथ की <orderedlist>
                 <listitem>
                   <para>DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS,
                     WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESSED OR
                     IMPLIED, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, WARRANTIES
                     THAT THE DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION OF THE
                     DOCUMENT IS FREE OF DEFECTS MERCHANTABLE, FIT FOR
                     A PARTICULAR PURPOSE OR NON-INFRINGING. THE ENTIRE
                     RISK AS TO THE QUALITY, ACCURACY, AND PERFORMANCE
                     OF THE DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION OF THE
                     DOCUMENT IS WITH YOU. SHOULD ANY DOCUMENT OR
                     MODIFIED VERSION PROVE DEFECTIVE IN ANY RESPECT,
                     YOU (NOT THE INITIAL WRITER, AUTHOR OR ANY
                     CONTRIBUTOR) ASSUME THE COST OF ANY NECESSARY
                     SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION. THIS DISCLAIMER
                     OF WARRANTY CONSTITUTES AN ESSENTIAL PART OF THIS
                     LICENSE. NO USE OF ANY DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED
                     VERSION OF THE DOCUMENT IS AUTHORIZED HEREUNDER
                     EXCEPT UNDER THIS DISCLAIMER; AND
                     UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES AND UNDER NO LEGAL
                     THEORY, WHETHER IN TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE),
                     CONTRACT, OR OTHERWISE, SHALL THE AUTHOR,
                     INITIAL WRITER, ANY CONTRIBUTOR, OR ANY
                     DISTRIBUTOR OF THE DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION
                     OF THE DOCUMENT, OR ANY SUPPLIER OF ANY OF SUCH
                     PARTIES, BE LIABLE TO ANY PERSON FOR ANY
                     DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, OR
                     CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OF ANY CHARACTER
                     INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, DAMAGES FOR LOSS
                     OF GOODWILL, WORK STOPPAGE, COMPUTER FAILURE OR
                     MALFUNCTION, OR ANY AND ALL OTHER DAMAGES OR
                     LOSSES ARISING OUT OF OR RELATING TO USE OF THE
                     DOCUMENT AND MODIFIED VERSIONS OF THE DOCUMENT,
                     EVEN IF SUCH PARTY SHALL HAVE BEEN INFORMED OF
                     THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.
                   </para>
                 </listitem>
           </orderedlist></para>
   </legalnotice>
